howardwilson

contact

howard@watsonbox.net

github.com/watsonbox watsonbox.github.com

languages

english mother tongue fluent french

programming

Ruby / Rails Ember.js, Swift, Python CSS3 & HTML5

profile

Highly motivated I.T. professional, capable of integrating quickly into existing teams, applying relevant skills and technologies where appropriate. Experienced in achieving the highest standards of development, with careful appreciation of project timescales and resource. Good communication skills; confident and articulate.

education

2001-2004 **Computer Science** BSc Hons The University of Warwick, England

First Class - 80% Average.

Third Year Project - 89% awarded 'Project of the Year 2004'.

experience

2014-Now	Freelance - Various Projects Ember.js, Swift/iOS, Docker/Dokku	Paris, France
2012–2014	Fanzy Technical Team Lead / CTO	Paris, France
	Ruby on Rails 3.2, Goliath, Sinatra, AWS/EC2/RDS, Elastics Social APIs, Scrum, TDD	earch, MongoDB,
2011-2012	eYeka Senior Developer / Technical Team Lead Ruby on Rails, Gigya Social Login/Sharing	Paris, France
2010-2011	Smartdate	Paris, France
	Senior Developer - Contract Ruby on Rails 2.3, AWS/EC2, NoSQL stores, memcach matching, Facebook Graph API, Scrum, TDD	ned, collaborative
2009-2010	Halogen Solutions Limited Managing Director - Self Employed Ruby on Rails 2.2, MySQL, Linux systems administration	Paris, France
2008-2009	Smart Business Communications EMEA e-Learning Project Manager - Contract PHP, MySQL, Ruby on Rails 2.1, Linux systems administration	Paris, France
2006-2008	RM Education PIc Technical Team Lead - Contract C#, ASP.NET, COM+, Transact-SQL	oidcot, Oxfordshire, UK
2006	Sygneca Ltd Web Application Developer - Contract Scala	esden, Hampshire, UK
2004-2006	Dorset Software Services .NET/C# Consultant Analyst Programmer	Poole, Dorset, UK